<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

<!-- General -->
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_1">
		<text> Here are the coordinates of the anomalies I'd like you to examine - with the help of a detector, you should be able to find some interesting samples. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_1">
		<text> Got it. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_2">
		<text> As you’ve no doubt already guessed, I work for the Institute for the Study of the Chernobyl Anomalous Zone’s scientific arm. Artifacts are invisible to the human eye, but they all emit frequencies that our detectors can pick up. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_2">
		<text>Well, I know that much. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_3">
		<text> Each artifact emits a unique energy frequency. It’s…how to say - like an imprint, like an author’s signature on a unique piece of art. The wider the scanning range of the detector, the more artifacts it can find. As a general rule, stalkers are only interested in artifacts with outstanding properties that provide practical benefits - anti-gravity artifacts to help them carry more, radiation-reducing artifacts to make exploring safer, and so on. For us scientists, though, any samples taken from anomalies are of great interest. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_3">
		<text> Uh-huh. Very interesting. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_4">
		<text> I’m sure you already know this, but Strelok managed to unravel the secret of the Zone’s origins, and that information has been widely disseminated amongst the wider scientific community. We’ve already seen huge advancements in terms of understanding anomalous phenomena, especially how said anomalies interact with the world around us and their effects on living organisms. This work is anything but simple - so we’re looking for helpers from amongst the free stalker community. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_4">
		<text> For a decent reward, of course. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_5">
		<text> The rupture of the noosphere - you might know it better as the second explosion - resulted in the creation of the Zone as we know it today. Lines of psi-fields wrap around the Zone like tentacles, and everything within the grasp of those arms is affected. Even you’ve been marked by the Zone. What can we say, then, about the artifacts born here, in the womb of the Zone? The Zone and all that comes with it are an incredible gift - one not that everyone can appreciate. And it’s not about the money, or the prestige! Artifacts are the messengers of the Zone - it’s how the Zone itself communicates to us. That’s why we need them so badly. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_5">
		<text> Not like you can eat the damn things, though. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_6">
		<text> Each artifact, as I mentioned, has a unique frequency - even if the artifacts in question belong to the same family. They can tell us so much - help us unravel the mysteries of the noosphere. Honestly, the dumbest thing you can do is jam them into a box, stick it onto your belt and pray it’ll deflect some bullets or save you from taking a course of antirads. We’re just starting to see the bigger picture - we’re planning on compiling a full spectrogram of the Zone, which means we’ll have to deal with the hostile nature of the terrain. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_6">
		<text> That’s great. What do you want me to do exactly?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_7">
		<text> Have you ever wondered what artifacts are made of? Most often, artifacts are the remains of living beings caught within an anomaly - so the next time you decide to show off a rare find, just remember: you could be proudly displaying the remains of some Stalker. Or a boar, or something. Who knows? </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_7">
		<text> I don’t make a habit of showing off. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_8">
		<text> Most people believe that anomalies are some kind of tear in the fabric of space-time, where the physical laws of our world break down. There are other theories, though; one point of view posits that anomalies are the result of some sort of signal that we - our reality - simply cannot receive. In that case, who is sending that signal, and why? Maybe…maybe it’s like our world is a pot, the lid rattling as the broth within begins to boil over. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_8">
		<text> All that matters is how we deal with it. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_9">
		<text> Anomalies generally choose organic samples as their targets - wild animals or zombies that are trapped and killed within said anomalies, for example. This is how artifacts appear. Knowing the exact origins of artifacts, we can analyse them with ease - no more difficult than reading a book or extracting data from a flash drive. </text>
	</string>
	<string id = "story_line_answer_9">
		<text> I hope you're not thinking about chucking test subjects into anomalies. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_10">
		<text> We don’t buy artifacts from stalkers or bandits. Without knowing the precise origin of said artifacts, they’re little more than irradiated bits of junk. Our task is different: to collect samples from every corner of the Zone for study. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_10">
		<text>Got it. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_11">
		<text> Every artifact, even those from the same family, have a unique radiological signature depending on the place of its origin. The Zone leaves a unique imprint on each one, ensuring that each sample is distinct from one another. With a full-spectrum radiation scan, we can use that data to create a psionic map of the Zone, delve into the disturbances that resulted in the formation of the Zone itself - perhaps even control the powers behind said disturbances ourselves. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_11">
		<text> How ambitious. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_12">
		<text> Thanks to you, our entire server cluster is working around the clock computing the data we have - it’ll take years to fully analyse all of it. In any case, despite the risks, our team has been divided across the entire territory of the Zone; our team lead, Academician Skabinsky, is planning far ahead. It’ll be impossible for one person alone to comprehend the entirety of the situation - it’s only by combining our deductive abilities that we’ll see success in this endeavour.  </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_12">
		<text> That's great. I'm really happy for you. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_13">
		<text> Thanks for sticking around. Usually the stalkers who help us just up and vanish. The preliminary analysis of the spectrogram is full of surprises - it looks like the centre of the Zone has been hiding right under our noses all this time. 
Our colleague didn’t wait for the final calculations and has already left for the site. Me, I’m inclined to complete the map. I need a few more samples.
 </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_13">
		<text> This will never end, will it? </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_14">
		<text> Our work is finally drawing to a close. Soon we’ll prove that we deserve to take our place…right. You’re aware that there is a giga-anomaly at the centre of the Zone, and that all of the lines of psi-fields intersect there? An artifact born at such a uniquely powerful place will have incredible properties. The Zone, at last, will speak to us. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_14">
		<text> With us? </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_dialog_15">
		<text> Sad news. Our colleague’s dropped off the network. There’s no reason to hope for the best - most likely, he’s died. The giga-anomaly in the centre of the Zone is still nigh-impossible to pass through; we’ll have to think about how to solve this problem. It might be worth taking another look at our calculations.  </text>
	</string>	
	<string id = "story_line_answer_15">
		<text> It’s the Zone. Nothing good comes from acting without thinking first. </text>
	</string>	
	
</string_table>
